(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
灼けつくような日差し
Burning sunlight
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
Spangles floating on the water's surface
はしゃぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Beneath the playful summer colors and backlighting
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
Awakening the youth of those days
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up the hem of my denim jeans
裸足で走ってる砂の上
Running barefoot across the sand
硝子の淵で回り回る
Spinning 'round the glass rim
輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
A shining lapis lazuli marble
なんだか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
Somehow, it's a thin line between that and your smile
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peering through the film, it's non-fiction
彩りに解されたメモリー
A memory unraveled by color
リセットなんて出来ないから
Because I can't just reset it
Love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Mid-Summer
アルゴリズムの中
Inside the algorithm
瞬速でダビングして
Dubbing at lightning speed
切り取ってきっとアイラ
Cut it out, it must be "Ila"
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it again
Le Lemon Lime Orange
君と一生分の思い出
A lifetime of memories with you
何気ない一日が
A casual day
One of a kind
イェーイ！
Yay!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
灼けつくような日差し
Burning sunlight
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
Spangles floating on the water's surface
はしゃぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Beneath the playful summer colors and backlighting
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
Awakening the youth of those days
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up the hem of my denim jeans
裸足で走ってる砂の上
Running barefoot across the sand
硝子の淵で回り回る
Spinning 'round the glass rim
輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
A shining lapis lazuli marble
なんだか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
Somehow, it's a thin line between that and your smile
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peering through the film, it's non-fiction
彩りに解されたメモリー
A memory unraveled by color
リセットなんて出来ないから
Because I can't just reset it
Love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Mid-Summer
アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
Inside the algorithm (Ooh)
瞬速でダビングして
Dubbing at lightning speed
切り取ってきっとアイラ
Cut it out, it must be "Ila"
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
This must be love (Ooh)
二度と忘れないように (Ok)
So I'll never forget it again (Ok)
Le Lemon Lime Orange
君と一生分の思い出 (Ok)
A lifetime of memories with you (Ok)
何気ない一日が
A casual day
One of a kind
氷が溶けては渦巻いた
Ice melting and swirling
魔法の杖代わりのマドラー
A stirrer instead of a magic wand
喉の奥くすぐる炭酸
Carbonation tickling the back of my throat
香る柑橘系のフレイバー
Scent of citrus flavor
爽やかな気流にのって
Riding on a refreshing breeze
波の還りを見守ってる Beachside
Watching the waves return at the beachside
あどけない面影に焦がれ
Yearning for that innocent look
微かに触れそうな指先
Fingertips almost touching
煌めきで上塗りしてしまおう
Let's coat it over with brilliance
Get ahead of what you used to be
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Mid-Summer
アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
Inside the algorithm (Ooh)
瞬速でダビングして
Dubbing at lightning speed
切り取ってきっとアイラ
Cut it out, it must be "Ila"
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
This must be love (Ooh)
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it again
ミッドサマーシトラス Oh yeah
Mid-Summer Citrus Oh yeah
いつだって We got love!! Okay
Always, we got love!! Okay
君といるだけで Feel so nice ココロはまた実り
Just being with you feels so nice, my heart ripens again
寝起きの太陽も 願ってもない三々五々
Even the sun just waking up, a lucky meeting of people
白飛びしてしまうほど 眩しいのは夏のせい
So bright it white-outs, the dazzle is all summer's fault
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, midsummer
アルゴリズムの中
Within the algorithm
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in a flash
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Cutting out the emotions
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it again
Le-Lemon Lime Orange
君と一生分の想い出
A lifetime of memories with you
何気ない一日が One of a kind
An ordinary day is one of a kind
はーい！
Hi~!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good work, everyone!
せーの、ReGLOSSにズームイン！
One, two, zoom in on ReGLOSS!
We are ReGLOSS!
じゃあ一人ずつ自己紹介やろー！
Now, let's introduce ourselves one by one!
響き渡れ奏で！
Resonate, Kanade!
ホロライブデバイス、リグロスのおんがくたまごから...
From Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's music egg...
...ニワトリになりました、音の瀬奏です！こんにちはー！
...I've become a chicken! I'm Otonose Kanade! Hello!
そしてー！
And next!
可愛いポジティブジーニアス！
The cute positive genius!
ホロライブデバイス、リグロスの一条莉々華だよ！イエーイ！
From Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS, I'm Ichijou Ririka! Yay!
そしてー！
And then!
ブンブブン！ホロライブデバイス...
Vroom vroom! Hololive DEV_IS...
...リグロスの番長、轟はじめっす！そしてー！
...ReGLOSS's leader, I'm Todoroki Hajime! And next!
はい、ホロライブデバイス、リグロスの人間失格オタク担当、
Yes, from Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS, in charge of being the 'No Longer Human' otaku,
儒烏風亭らでんでございます！イエーイ！
I'm Juufuutei Raden! Yay!
いきなりでしたが、なんと新曲を披露させていただきました！
It was sudden, but we just performed our new song!
みんな、どうだった？
How was it, everyone?
本当にごめんなさい！
I'm so sorry!
本当に申し訳ないです！
I'm truly sorry!
最初さ、あの、これぜひアーカイブでも見返してほしいんですけど、
At the beginning, I'd really like you to watch this again in the archive...
我々が足でジャンケンをするっていう...
We did rock-paper-scissors with our feet...
そう、あっち向いてホイをするシーンがあるんだよね。
Yeah, there's a scene where we play "look over there."
そこで、事前の打ち合わせと違うものが出てしまって、
And there, something different from our rehearsal happened,
あっち向いてホイをするっていう。
playing "look over there."
しかも1回もあっち向いてホイ成功しなかったのに、
And even though we didn't succeed once,
なんか莉々華が勝ったことになって。
it somehow ended up with Ririka winning.
でもソロのパート頑張んなきゃって思ってたのに、声めっちゃ震えてた。
I thought I had to do my best for my solo, but my voice was shaking so much.
笑い声、聞こえちゃってたのかな。
I wonder if the audience could hear our laughter.
聞こえてたと思うよ、笑ってるなーみたいな。
I think so. They were probably like, "They're laughing."
まぁ、こういうのも生配信、ライブの醍醐味でございます。
Well, this is the best part of a live stream and a live performance.
1回目だからバレてないやろ、ああいうものだと思われてるかも。
Since it's the first time, maybe they didn't notice. They might think it's supposed to be like that.
そんな「ミッドサマーシトラス」なんですが、なんと、もうすでにMVが公開されております！
Regarding "Midsummer Citrus," believe it or not, the MV has already been released!
せっかくなんで一人ずつ感想聞いていきますか？じゃあはじめから。
Since we're here, let's hear everyone's thoughts one by one. Starting with Hajime.
夏って言ったらハッピーハッピーって感じなのかなと思ったら、
I thought summer would be all "happy happy," but...
ちょっとノスタルジックな、エモい感じの、
it's a bit nostalgic and emotional.
過去を彷彿とさせる、いい夏の思い出みたいな感じでエモい曲だなって思ってます。
It feels like a good summer memory that reminds you of the past. I think it's an emotional song.
やっぱり制服着てたりしてたから、学生時代のことを思い出したりしたし、
Since we were wearing uniforms, it made me think back to my student days.
すごい爽やかな夏曲だったから、暑い夏の日に聞きながら歩いてたら涼しくなるのかなって思いました。
It's such a refreshing summer song that I thought walking while listening to it on a hot day would cool me down.
MVに私たちのカット、青くんのも含めて、リグロスのカットがたくさん入ってて、
The MV has many cuts of us, including Ao-kun's. There are so many ReGLOSS cuts.
それを見てるだけですごいニヤニヤしちゃった。
Just watching that made me grin so much.
サビの冒頭、「踊ってミッドサマー」ってある通り、
As the beginning of the chorus goes, "Dance, midsummer,"
すごく乗りやすくて踊りやすい曲なんじゃないかなと思いますんで、
I think it's a song that's very easy to get into and dance to.
ぜひ皆さんも踊ってミッドサマーやってください。
So please, everyone, try dancing along to "Midsummer Citrus."
今回のMVに関わってくださった監督、クリエイターの皆様、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to the director and creators who worked on this MV!
そしてついに！明日0時、
And finally! At 0:00 tomorrow,
つまり今日の24時に、「ミッドサマーシトラス」デジタルリリースされます！
meaning at 24:00 today, "Midsummer Citrus" will be digitally released!
オートラさん、前島宗司さんに
Created by Ohtora-san and
手がけていただいた、爽やかなメロディーと
Soushi Maejima-san, the refreshing melody and
心地よいリズムが、夏の暑さを吹き飛ばしてくれるような一曲でございます。
pleasant rhythm make it a song that blows away the summer heat.
ぜひこの夏はミッドサマーシトラスを聴いて、
Please listen to Midsummer Citrus this summer,
ReGLOSSとの夏の思い出たくさん作りましょう！
and let's make many summer memories with ReGLOSS!
作りましょうー！
Let's make them!
みんなよろしくねー！お願いしまーす！
Hope you enjoy it! Here we go!
ということで今日はね、ここから、
So today, from here,
まあ別のまた夏曲を歌っていこうと思うんですけど...
I'm thinking of singing some other summer songs...
事前にね、アンケートで皆さんに
We'll also sing the ones you all
候補を挙げてもらったのも歌いますので、楽しみにしててくださーい！
suggested in the survey beforehand, so look forward to it!
じゃあちょっとね、真夏のビーチということで、
Well, since it's a midsummer beach
あまりにも暑くて倒れてしまいそうなので、移動しますか。
and it's so hot I might collapse, shall we move?
移動しましょうー！
Let's move!
あ、砂が熱い！熱い熱い！
Ah, the sand is hot! Hot, hot!
熱い熱い熱い！
Hot, hot, hot!
しばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment
強制カットやって...
The cut was forced...
じゃあ行きましょうか、次は。
Well, let's go, next.
どこ行こうかね。
Where should we go?
やっちまったー。
I blew it.
何やっちまったんだっけ？
What did you blow?
何もやっちまってないよ、大丈夫だよ。
I didn't blow anything, it's fine.
カラオケ向かいますか。
Shall we head to karaoke?
カラオケ行こう行こう。
Let's go to karaoke!
行きましょうか。
Let's go.
カラオケ行くにょ。
Going to karaoke.
カラオケ！カラオケで歌うんだからね。
Karaoke! Because we're gonna sing at karaoke.
歌うならやっぱカラオケっしょ。
If you're gonna sing, it's gotta be karaoke.
会員証持ってる？
Do you have your membership card?
会員証持ってるよ！アプリ！
I have my membership card! On the app!
アプリ、アプリダウンロードしてないかも。
The app? I might not have downloaded it.
あ、でもカードで持ってるから大丈夫。
Ah, but I have the physical card, so it's okay.
あ、すごーい。
Oh, amazing.
会員証強！
Strong membership game!
すごいなー。
That's impressive.
えー、何歌おうかなー。
Hmm, what should I sing?
えー、悩むねー。
Hmm, hard to decide.
リクエストをね、頂いておりますから。
Well, we've received requests.
ありがたいにょー。
So grateful.
みんなのリクエスト、ありがたいにょ。
Grateful for everyone's requests.
もしかしたら選ばれるかもしれないよ。
Maybe your request will be chosen.
ミッドサマーシトラス？
Midsummer Citrus?
歌ったでしょ、さっき。
We just sang that.
歌ったのににょー。
We already sang it.
あ、じゃんけんのやり直しから。
Ah, let's redo the rock-paper-scissors.
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽん！
First comes rock, rock-paper-scissors!
あっち向いてホイ！
Look that way!
カラオケ着いたー！
We're at the karaoke place!
あ、ポスターあるじゃん！
Oh, there's a poster!
ホントだ！
It's true!
ポスター！
A poster!
急にポスター出てきたからびっくりした。
I was surprised because a poster suddenly appeared.
カラオケにあるわけないでしょ、やだー。
No way there'd be one in a karaoke room, oh my.
すごいなー、じゃあ座りますか。
Incredible. Well, shall we sit down?
ちょっとドリンク湧いてくるけど、なんかいる？
I'm gonna go get drinks, want anything?
え、じゃあ、コーンスープ！
Um, then, corn soup!
リリカにコーンスープと、あとカルピス2個ほしい。
Corn soup for Ririka, and I want two Calpis.
え、じゃあ俺ウーロン茶。
Then, I'll have an oolong tea.
じゃあ全部に、上にソフトクリームつけといて。
Then, put soft-serve ice cream on top of all of them.
なんでだよ！
Why?!
嫌がらせしてるの？
Are you picking on us?
あ、そっかそっか。
Ah, right, right.
はい、じゃあ時間もないので、早速歌っていこうと思いまーす！
Okay, since we're short on time, let's start singing right away!
何歌うのかなー、楽しみだねー。
What are we gonna sing? I'm excited.
一番最初に歌いたい人、誰ですかー？
Who wants to sing first?
はい！
Me!
番長ー！
Bancho!
行くじゃ！
Here I go!
あのミッドサマーシトラスであんだけ歌って踊った後に、
After singing and dancing that much to Midsummer Citrus,
一発目この元気良さで行ける人なかなかいないよ。
there aren't many people who could start off with this much energy.
さすが番長。
As expected of Bancho.
夏盛り上げていくじゃ！
Let's heat up the summer!
じゃあそんな番長からいきましょー、お願いしまーす！
Well then, let's start with Bancho. Take it away!
真夏のSounds good!
Manatsu no Sounds good!
「サンオイル
"Put some sun oil
背中に塗って！」と
on my back!"
水着の上
Undoing your swimsuit
外しなから寝そべった
as you lay down
大胆な
Those bold
君の一言は
words of yours
甘ったるい匂いがした
had a sweet scent to them
どこまでも
The endless
青い海と空
blue sea and sky
僕たちの関係に似てる
resemble our relationship
水平線は
The horizon
交わってるのに
is meeting together
そう今はまだ
but for now you're still
わがままな
just like a
妹のようさ
selfish little sister
真夏のSounds good!
Manatsu no Sounds good!
つぶやきながら
As I whisper those words
次のステップへ進みたいね
I want to move on to the next step
恋のカリキュラム
The curriculum of love
波音Sounds good!
Namio no Sounds good!
心が騒ぐよ
My heart is racing
去年よりも
More than last year
僕は本気になる
I'm getting serious
砂浜で
On the sandy beach
肌を焼いている
as you're tanning
君を置いて
leaving you behind
僕は一人泳いだ
I went swimming alone
真夏のSounds good!
Midsummer's Sounds good!
僕は一人泳いだぜ
I swam all alone
その後のいきなりのキスは
The sudden kiss that followed...
塩辛い味がした
...tasted salty
さっきまでのあの風景とは
Compared to the scenery from just now...
空気まで変わった気がする
I feel like even the air has changed
海と空がちゃんと向き合って
The sea and sky face each other squarely...
そうお互いのその青さ
...reflecting each other's...
映し合っている
...vivid blue
渚のGood job!
Good job on the shore!
愛しい人よ
My beloved
ずっと切なくて言えなかった
I couldn't say it, it was always too painful
君が近すぎて
You were too close
きっかけGood job!
Good job on the chance!
素直になるんだ
I'm going to be honest
手を伸ばそう
Let's reach out our hands
恋の季節じゃないか！
Isn't it the season for love!
真夏のSounds good!
Midsummer's Sounds good!
つぶやきながら
While whispering...
次のステップへ進みたいね
I want to move to the next step
恋のカリキュラム
The curriculum of love
波音Sounds good!
The sound of waves, Sounds good!
心が騒ぐよ
My heart is pounding
去年よりも
More than last year...
僕は本気になる
...I'm getting serious
真夏のSounds good!
Midsummer's Sounds good!
君が好きだ
I love you
波音Sounds good!
Wave sound, Sounds good!
やっと言えたよ
I finally said it
渚のGood job!
Good job on the shore!
君が好きだ
I love you
きっかけGood job!
Good job on the chance!
いいタイミングだね
It's perfect timing
真夏のSounds good!
Midsummer's Sounds good!
1曲目からぶち上がっていく！
Starting off with a bang from the first song!
ああ、いい曲ですね。
Ah, it's a great song.
なんか枝豆とビールもらっていいっすか？
Can I get some edamame and beer?
お酒飲もうとしてる。
She's trying to drink alcohol!
ちょっとおっさんを入れちゃいました、今。
I kind of let my "middle-aged man" side out just now.
ちょっとキラキラしすぎてて。
It was a bit too sparkly.
ちなみに何でさ、この曲にしたの？はじめちゃん。
By the way, why did you choose this song, Hajime-chan?
アンケートにあって、歌えるのでチェックを入れた。
It was in the questionnaire, and I checked it because I can sing it.
もうちょっとあるでしょ、こういうところが好きとかさ。
Surely there's more? Like, "I like this part" or something.
いや、でもすごいでしょ、白い砂浜、青い空、白いビキニの美少女たちがキャーってやってる姿が浮かび上がるのが、すごく素敵じゃないでしょうか。
No, but it's great, right? The image of beautiful girls in white bikinis on a white beach under a blue sky, going "kyaa!"—isn't that just wonderful?
なるほどね、素敵だった。
I see, it was lovely.
しかも盛り上がるね、初めて聴いたんだけど。
And it's really hype. It was my first time hearing it.
ダンスも準備してきたの？
Did you prepare the dance too?
いや、ノリあれ。
No, that was just the vibe.
本家のダンスと別にあって、それはちょっとごめんなさい覚えてきてないんですけど。
There's a different original dance, but sorry, I didn't memorize that one.
でも即興でやったってことだよね、今。
But that means you did it impromptu just now.
ノリで。
Just with the flow.
はじめちゃんありがとう！
Thank you, Hajime-chan!
もうプロだったよね今ね。
You were totally professional just now.
ウェーブとかやばかった。
Those wave moves were insane.
はじめちゃんに拍手！
Applause for Hajime-chan!
次！じゃあ次どうする？
Next! So, what's next?
この後歌いたい人いるわけないじゃん。
There's no way anyone wants to sing after that!
でも一応台本だと奏になってるけど。
But the script says it's Kanade's turn.
頑張れ、奏準備大丈夫？
Good luck! Kanade, you ready?
はい、いきます！
Yes, here I go!
じゃあ音楽お願いします！
Music, please!
いつものあれください。
Give me the usual.
いつものあれ？ビール？
The usual? Beer?
少女レイ
Shoujo Rei
本能が狂い始める
Instincts start to go mad
追い詰められたハツカネズミ
A cornered mouse
今、絶望の淵に立って
Now, standing on the edge of despair...
踏切へと飛び出した
...I leaped toward the railroad crossing
そう君は友達
Yes, you are my friend
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab my hand
そう君は独りさ
Yes, you are alone
居場所なんて無いだろ
You have nowhere to belong, right?
…降り立った　居場所なんて無いだろ
…descended, there's no place for you here, right?
二人きりこのまま
Just the two of us, like this.
愛し合えるさー
We can love each other.
繰り返す　フラッシュバック　蝉の声
Recurring flashbacks, the sound of cicadas.
二度とは帰らぬ君
You, who will never return.
永遠に千切れてく
Tearing apart for eternity.
お揃いのキーホルダー
Matching keychains.
夏が消し去った
Summer has swept them away.
白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin.
哀しい程
So much that it's sad.
とり憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be completely possessed.
本性が暴れ始める
One's true nature starts to run wild.
九月のスタート　告げるチャイム
The chime signaling the start of September.
次の標的に置かれた花瓶
The vase placed on the next target's desk.
仕掛けたのは僕だった
I was the one who set it up.
そう　君が悪いんだよ
That's right, it's your fault.
僕だけを見ててよ
Look only at me.
そう　君の苦しみ
Yes, your suffering...
助けが欲しいだろ
...you want help, don't you?
溺れてく其の手に
In those drowning hands...
そっと口吻（KISS）をした
...I gently placed a kiss.
薄笑いの獣たち
The beasts with faint smirks.
その心晴れるまで
Until that heart clears.
爪を突き立てる
Digging in their claws.
不揃いのスカート
Uneven skirts.
夏の静寂を切り裂くような悲鳴が
A scream that seems to tear through the summer silence.
木霊する教室の窓には青空
Echoing through the classroom windows is the blue sky.
そう　君は友達
That's right, you're a friend.
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab my hand.
そう　君は友達
That's right, you're a friend.
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab my hand.
そう　君が居なくちゃ　居場所なんて無いんだよ
That's right, without you, there's no place for me.
透き通った世界で　愛し合えたらー
If we could love each other in this transparent world...
繰り返す　フラッシュバック　蝉の声
Recurring flashbacks, the sound of cicadas.
二度とは帰らぬ君
You, who will never return.
永遠に千切れてく
Tearing apart for eternity.
お揃いのキーホルダー
Matching keychains.
夏が消し去った
Summer has swept them away.
白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin.
哀しい程
So much that it's sad.
とり憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be completely possessed.
透明な君は
Transparent you...
僕を指差してたー
...were pointing at me.
少女レイでしたー！
That was "Otome Rei"!
一気にエモい気分になったね
It suddenly felt so emotional, didn't it?
奏のやっぱ綺麗なさ、透き通るような声にめちゃくちゃ合ってる曲だよねこれ
This song really suits Kanade's beautiful, clear voice, doesn't it?
嬉しいー！嬉しいー！
I'm so happy! I'm so happy!
アンケートでもね、奏にぜひ奏に歌ってほしいっていうのもあったみたいだよ
In the survey, it seems there were requests for Kanade to sing this song.
センス良い！リクエストした人！
Great taste, the person who requested this!
最高！そのコメントした人！
You're the best, the person who made that comment!
奏の後も奏の後で相当なハードル上がってるんですけども
The bar has been set quite high after Kanade's performance.
じゃあ、帰りますねー
Then, I'm going home!
早い早いw お疲れ様でしたw
Too soon! Good work! (laughs)
まだ帰らないで
Don't leave yet.
もう今奏に選ばれてちょっとドキドキしてるんで
I'm feeling a bit nervous now that Kanade chose me.
選ばれたんならさ、じゃあ次はチョイスした方の歌じゃないですか？
If you were chosen, then next should be the song for the one who made the choice, right?
頑張って歌います！
I'll do my best singing!
おおー！行けー！楽しみー！
Whoo! Go for it! I'm excited!
楽しみー。ん、じゃあ行きます、お願いします！
I'm excited. Okay, here I go. Please start the music!
HANABI
水野良樹 詞曲
Lyrics & Composition by Yoshiki Mizuno
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
蒼き夢　舞い放つ
scattering blue dreams.
花　燃えゆく
The flowers are burning away...
懐かしい曲！
What a nostalgic song!
大好きこの曲！
I love this song!
静寂に落ちる空
The sky falling into silence,
ふたひらの夢花火
like two dream fireworks.
彼方に旅立つ
They depart for the distance.
あなたも見えたの？
Could you see it too?
おなじ光が
That same light.
離れてもいつの日か
Even if we're apart, I believe
出逢えると信じてる
that someday we'll meet again.
胸裂く想いをあなたに
With these heart-wrenching feelings for you...
歌う声が聴こえる？
Can you hear my singing voice?
せつなに開くそれは　HANABI
Blooming in a moment, those are fireworks.
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
蒼き夢　舞い放つ
scattering blue dreams.
咲き誇れ遥か高く
Bloom proudly, far and high.
守りゆくその想い
Protecting those feelings,
ひたすら鳴り響け
let them echo on and on.
果てるまでせめて強く
At least until the end, be strong.
此の花　燃えゆく
This flower is burning away...
いくつもの言の葉を
So many words
悪戯に散らかした
were scattered playfully.
断ちゆく迷いは
The hesitations being cut away
静かに消えたの
quietly disappeared.
明日が見えてる？
Can you see tomorrow?
せつなに開くそれは　HANABI
Blooming in a moment, those are fireworks.
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
つかみゆく幻の花
reaching for a phantom flower,
あたしの手を零れ落ちて
it spills through my hands.
願うままこの想い
Just as I wish, let these feelings
あなたに鳴り渡れ
resound to you.
果てるまでせめて強く
At least until the end, be strong.
此の花　燃えゆく
This flower is burning away...
せつなに開くそれは　HANABI
Blooming in a moment, those are fireworks.
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
蒼き夢　舞い上がれ
soar high, blue dreams.
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
蒼き夢　舞い上がれ
soar high, blue dreams.
いつの日かめぐり逢えて
That someday we'll meet again...
繋ぎゆくこの想い
these feelings that connect us.
愛しき君　我
My beloved, and me,
いつまでも双片強く
always strongly together.
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
蒼き夢　舞い放つ
scattering blue dreams.
煌めいて　揺らめいて
Sparkling and wavering,
蒼き夢　舞い放つ
scattering blue dreams.
咲き誇れ遥か高く
Bloom proudly, far and high.
守りゆくその想い
Protecting those feelings,
ひたすら鳴り響け
let them echo on and on.
果てるまでせめて強く
At least until the end, be strong.
此の花　燃えゆく
This flower is burning away...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よいしょ！めっちゃよかっちゃん。
Heave-ho! That was so good.
嬉しい！すごいさ、リリカに合ってるねこの曲。
I'm so happy! It really suits you, Ririka.
ほんと？合ってる？
Really? It suits me?
え、めっちゃ嬉しい。これすごい大好きなアニメの、BLEACHのアニメの曲なんだけど。
Wow, I'm so glad. This is from an anime I love, the BLEACH anime.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
そう、いっぱい聴いてた曲だったから、歌いたかったの。
Yeah, I used to listen to it a lot, so I really wanted to sing it.
いいね！いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
That's great! Nice, nice!
すごくよかった。
It was really good.
でも、ってことは次はらでんちゃんの番？
But, does that mean it's Raden-chan's turn next?
番じゃん
It's your turn.
なん、え、え、番っしょ
Wh- Wait, it's definitely your turn.
君だ！
It's you!
番？
My turn?
じゃあちょっと、ここでまた盛り上がる系の曲を...
Then, I think I'll go with another high-energy song...
いこうかなと思います！
...here!
おー！
Ohh!
楽しみ！
Can't wait!
さあ、チャトラの皆さん、ENJOYの準備をお願いしまーす！
Now, everyone in Chatora, please get ready to ENJOY!
ENJOYね
ENJOY, right.
それじゃあ、いきましょう、準備OKです！
Well then, let's go, I'm ready!
ココロオドル
Kokoro Odoru
いきましょう、ココロオドル！
Let's go, Kokoro Odoru!
みんな一緒に盛り上がってください！
Everyone, please have a great time together!
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY the music keeps on playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい 胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN the heartbeat I want to deliver
ココロオドル アンコール わかす
Heart dancing, raising the encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO)
今 ゴーイング ゴーリンより
Now, more than going go-in
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Jumping over, riding the sound, keep swimming
ENJOY (ENJOY)
IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Responding hearts keep echoing
のってきな的な言葉が出てきた
Words that make you groove came out
ここは心踊るところだから
Because this is a place where your heart dances
置いてかないよ 追い付きたいなら
I won't leave you behind, if you want to catch up
Get Up Stand Up 行くしかねぇ
Get Up Stand Up, you just gotta go
つかねぇやっぱ気付いたんだ100%
Wait, I realized it, 100%
幸せの意思表示 鳴らせCLAP CLAP
Expression of happiness, let the CLAP CLAP sound
仲間同士 夜通し 詰め込んだ
Packed with friends through the night
アッパーなテンションのシチュエーション
A situation with high tension
Have a dreamin' グリーディング
Have a dreamin' greeting
この場の空気 中心
Center of the atmosphere here
サークル 繋がる ブギー
Circles connecting, Boogie
フリーキー きばらず
Freaky, without tension
ここのみんなと その価値あるから
With everyone here, because it's worth it
Swing swing sing a song
生真面目 恥ずかしがりでもできる
Even if you're serious and shy, you can do it
イマジネーション 望むところだ
Imagination, just what I wanted
茶の間 床の間 ところ構わず
Living room, alcove, no matter where
ボタンひとつで踊る心が
With just one button, your heart dances
やっぱりな Hurry up
As I thought, Hurry up
俺は急いで歯を磨く
I hurry and brush my teeth
手間は取らせんさぁ見な
I won't take much time, so look
あみ出すうか 勝手心騒ぎ出す
I'll create it, my heart starts pounding on its own
時間場所など限らず
Regardless of time or place
グーたらてきぱき日常メリハリ
Lazy and brisk, daily life modulation
毎日変わる音 フレッシュデリバリー
The sound that changes daily, fresh delivery
揺らすBody Rock 増々
Shaking Body Rock, more and more
ベクトル向かう矛先はプラスへ
The vector is pointing towards positive
その長と短そこがどうかなる
The long and short of it, how will it turn out
所々ココロゴト転がしあう
Rolling hearts here and there
だから今日は今日振り切る昨日
So today is today, shaking off yesterday
心から踊らすこの一時
Making the heart dance, this moment
一度Go ドア開けたらフロア
Go once, open the door and it's the floor
浮き足立つ 抜け出す 揺れるCore
Restless, breaking out, shaking Core
Up and down こっち
Up and down, over here
タンタ Tap Let's Dance
Tanta Tap Let's Dance
Come on 加速 構うもんかもう
Come on, accelerate, I don't care anymore
いてもたってもいらんない
I can't just sit still
心だけじゃ収まんないぜ
It's not enough just for the heart
Day and Night Shake a body
ぎこちないなら脱いで
If you're awkward, strip it off
可愛い心感じるままに
Just as your cute heart feels
LA LA LA LA LIVE LIVE
GOOD TO BE ALIVE 笑い愛し愛され
GOOD TO BE ALIVE, laughing, loving and being loved
喜怒哀楽刻もう音と言葉
Let's carve emotions, sounds and words
つなぐこの場 届いてるなら MAKE SOME NOISE
Connecting this place, if it reaches you, MAKE SOME NOISE
グレートフル 描くスケールはでかく
Grateful, the scale I draw is big
楽しいもんだ エラクデラックス
It's fun, tremendously deluxe
狙う暇なんか 単純に簡単
No time to aim, simply easy
預けてカウントダウン 3・2・1
Leave it to the countdown 3, 2, 1
なりふり構わず 夢中で駆け抜けろ
Regardless of appearance, run through frantically
息まいて It's like this
Breathing hard, it's like this
さらに深い感動へ
Towards even deeper emotion
モーレツ Oh yes ココロオドル今日へ
Violently, oh yes, to the heart-dancing today
イエーイ！最高！ありがとうございました！
Yay! The best! Thank you so much!
らでん、レッツゴー！
Raden, Let's Go!
かっこいい！
So cool!
すごい！最高！
Amazing! The best!
心躍っちゃったわ
My heart really danced
楽しい曲だ！
What a fun song!
一人で歌う曲ではないよ...
It's not a song to be sung alone...
それは本当にそう
That's definitely true
でもすごいね、出し切ったね
But it was amazing, you gave it your all
出し切ったよ
I gave it my all
すごいエネルギー感じたもん今
I felt so much energy just now
今日もう歌えない？
Can you not sing anymore today?
いやいや、まだ一週しかしてないですけれど...
No no, we've only done one round...
さあ、次は誰歌う？
Alright, who's singing next?
次奏ちゃん歌うか。
How about Kanade goes next?
ええ？！ええ？！
What?! What?!
歌っちゃう？
I'm really doing it?
歌っちゃう！
You're doing it!
なんだろう、いいよ、じゃあ番長のセンスに任せるわ。
Well, okay then. I'll leave the choice to Bancho's taste.
あ、いいよ私のセンスで。オッケーオッケー。
Oh, sure, leave it to me. Okay, okay.
オッケー、じゃあ奏準備オッケー？
Okay. Kanade, you ready?
うん。はい。お願いしまーす！
Yep. Okay. Here I go!
お願いしまーす。
Take it away!
おおー！
Whooa!
いい曲きた！
A classic!
テンション上げ上げ！
Let's pump it up!
Na na na na na na na na na...
チョットでいいから　見せてくれないか
Just a little, won't you show me?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンで　オレ　メロメロ
Your sexy pheromones leave me head over heels.
Ah ふれちゃいそう　でもイケナイの！
Ah, it feels like we're touching, but it's forbidden!
徐々に高なる鼓動　止められないわ
My heart's beating faster and faster, I can't stop it.
交わす言葉の記憶遠く　口元の動きに揺れ動く
The memory of the words we exchanged is far away,
I'm swayed by the movement of your lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた　そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair, and then... Ah.
ABC 続かない　そんなんじゃダメじゃない
ABC won't follow, that's just not good enough, is it?
だってココロの奥は　違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, it's different, isn't it?
オレの青春　そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't just about that.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to go all the way in a burning heat.
きっとキミじゃなきゃやだよ　オレはイケナイ太陽
It has to be you, I'm the forbidden sun.
「赤い糸」なんて絵空事　でも下心でさえ信じたいの
A 'red thread of fate' is just a dream,
but I want to believe even in base desires.
俺は正しい　キミも正しい　とにかくもう左右されないぜ
I'm right, and you're right, anyway I won't be swayed anymore.
騙し騙され胸うずく　下手な芝居がより盛り上げる夜
Deceiving and being deceived, my chest aches,
a clumsy performance only heats up the night.
息が耳に触れた二人 Ah
Breaths touched ears, the two of us... Ah.
ABC 続かない　そんなんじゃダメじゃない
ABC won't follow, that's just not good enough, is it?
だってココロの奥は　違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, it's different, isn't it?
あたしの青春　そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't just about that.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to go all the way in a burning heat.
きっとキミじゃなきゃやだよ　あたしイケナイ太陽
It has to be you, I'm the forbidden sun.
交わす言葉の記憶遠く　口元の動きに揺れ動く
The memory of the words we exchanged is far away,
I'm swayed by the movement of your lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた　そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair, and then... Ah.
ABC ABC 続かない
ABC ABC won't follow.
だってココロの奥は　違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, it's different, isn't it?
オレの青春　そんなもんじゃない　熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't just about that, I want to go all the way in a burning heat.
きっとキミじゃなきゃやだよ　オレはイケナイ太陽
It has to be you, I'm the forbidden sun.
絡み合う糸は　君と俺を結ぶ赤い糸
The intertwined threads are the red thread that binds you and me.
あつい！
That was hot!
凄かったー！
That was amazing!
いや、この曲、番長のセクシーが溢れてていいですね。
Man, this song really brought out Bancho's sexy side, it's great.
ええ、ちょっとね、アチチになりましたね。
Yeah, it got a little 'achichi' in here.
アチチだね。
So 'achichi'.
アチチだよ。
It's scorching.
激アツ。あと社長の動きも激アツで。
Super intense. And the Prez's moves were intense too.
いや、社長の。お上手。歌なんだから。
Oh, Prez. You're so skilled. Since it's singing, after all.
踊りか〜いってね。
Thinking 'Is this a dance show?!'
いや、凄かった。
But man, it was incredible.
いや、楽しかったです。
Yeah, that was fun.
急に、あの、平成ですね、さっきから。
Suddenly, it feels like we're back in the Heisei era.
そうだね。夏メロというかなんというか。
True. It's like a 'Natsumelo' classic.
出たばっかりだからね、令和になった。
Since we only just moved into Reiwa, you know.
お腹の底から痛くなってきたな。
I'm starting to get butterflies in my stomach.
さあ、そういう感じの選曲も続きますよということで。
Well then, we've got more songs like that coming up.
奏とらでんの番なんじゃないの？
Isn't it Kanade and Raden's turn?
えー？
Eh?
いいじゃん。
Good idea.
ちょっとこう、結構ね、ヒートアップしちゃったから。
I've gotten a bit heated up, you see.
一旦クールダウンしようかね。
Let's cool down for a moment.
クールダウン？
Cool down?
らでんの体力も持ちませんから。
My stamina won't hold out otherwise.
ちょっとゆっくりした曲をね。はい。
So, a bit of a slower song. Yes.
はい、じゃあ二人とも準備してくださいね。
Alright, then both of you please get ready.
はーい。
Oka-y.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
準備いいですか？
Are you ready?
はい！
Yes!
はい。それじゃあ…
Yes. Well then...
あれ？座って歌う？
Wait, are we singing sitting down?
いや、立つ。
No, we stand.
あ、立ってるかな？立ってるわ。
Ah, are we standing? We're standing.
立ったー！
We stood up!
心も踊ってきた。
My heart's starting to dance too.
では、音楽お願いします。
Now then, music please.
踊っちゃだめよ。
Don't dance, okay?
後だった。
That was for afterwards.
プラネタリウム
愛　詞・曲
Planetarium
Lyrics & Music by Ai
夕月夜 顔だす
The evening moon peeks out
消えてく子供の声
Fading voices of children
遠く遠くこの空のどこかに
Far, far away, somewhere in this sky
君はいるんだろう
I'm sure you are there
夏の終わりに 二人で抜け出した
At the end of summer, we slipped away together
この公園で見つけた
We found it in this park
あの星座 何だか覚えてる？
Do you remember that constellation?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness
あの香りとともに
Along with that scent
花火がぱっと開く
Fireworks suddenly burst open
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to run to you right now
まっ暗で 何も見えない
It's pitch black and I can't see anything
怖くても 大丈夫
But even if I'm scared, it's okay
数えきれない 星空が
The countless stars in the sky
今もずっと ここにあるんだよ
They are still right here, even now
泣かないよ 昔 君と見た
I won't cry, because it was a beautiful sky...
きれいな空だったから
...that I saw with you long ago
あの道まで 響く
Resonating all the way to that road
靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of footsteps lingers in my ears
大きな自分の影を
Looking at my own large shadow
見つめて想うのでしょう
I suppose you're thinking
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though nothing should have changed
せつない気持ち ふくらんでく
This painful feeling keeps growing
どんなに想ったって
No matter how much I think of you
君はもういない
You are no longer here
行きたいよ 君のそばに
I want to go to your side
小さくても 小さくても
Even if it's just a little, just a little
１番に君が好きだよ
I love you more than anyone else
強くいられる
I can stay strong
願いを 流れ星に
To the shooting star
そっと 唱えてみたけれど
I softly whispered my wish
泣かないよ 届くだろう
I won't cry, surely it will reach
きれいな空に
The beautiful sky
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness
あの香りとともに
Along with that scent
花火がぱっと開く
Fireworks suddenly burst open
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are
小さな手を にぎりしめて
Clasping my small hands tight
泣きたいよ それはそれは
I want to cry, it was such a
きれいな空だった
beautiful sky
願いを 流れ星に
To the shooting star
そっと 唱えてみたけれど...
I softly whispered my wish...
願いを流れ星に
I whispered a wish to a falling star
そっと唱えてみたけれど
Softly and quietly
泣きたいよ...
I want to cry...
届かない...
I can't reach you...
想いをこの空に...
Sending my feelings to this sky...
イエーイ！
Yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
すごーい！
That was amazing!
ハイタッチ！ハイタッチまじで！
High five! Seriously, high five!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ごめん
Sorry.
ちょっと悲しい感じのやつ
That was a bit of a sad one.
はい！プラネタリウムでした！
Alright! That was Planetarium!
よかった〜！
That was great!
もうライブパフォーマンスやん、マジで
That was like a real live performance, seriously.
凄すぎるやろ
It's just too good.
よっしゃ、もう一回聞きたい
Alright, I want to hear it again.
もうあの、体力がないです、私
I... I don't have any stamina left.
あ、そっか。体力か
Ah, right. Stamina.
じゃあ、奏、歌う？一緒に
Well then, Kanade, shall we sing together?
いいよ！
Sure!
あんたも歌いたい、みんなで、歌いたい！
You want to sing too? Let's all sing!
何歌う？何歌う？
What should we sing? What should we sing?
ノリノリ...あの曲行っちゃいますか？
Something upbeat... Shall we go with THAT song?
何何？
Which one?
なんだろう...
I wonder what it is...
やっぱお星様がキラキラしたら、もう一回キラキラしたいんじゃない？
Since the stars were sparkling, don't you want to sparkle one more time?
お！プラネタリウムから、外に出ちゃう？
Oh! Are we going outside the planetarium?
それ！
That's it!
何の曲かな？
I wonder what song it is?
じゃあ行きましょう、お願いします！
Alright, let's go! Music, please!
どっちからだっけ？
Who starts again?
奏から、あ、奏から
It's Kanade. Ah, Kanade starts.
午前二時 フミキリに 望遠鏡を担いでった
At 2 AM, by the railroad crossing, I carried my telescope
ベルトに結んだラジオ 雨は降らないらしい
With a radio tied to my belt, they said it wouldn't rain
二分後に君が来た 大袈裟な荷物しょって来た
Two minutes later you arrived, carrying a huge bag on your back
始めようか 天体観測 ほうき星を探して
Shall we start our stargazing, searching for a comet?
深い闇に飲まれないように 精一杯だった
I was doing my best not to be swallowed by the deep darkness
君の震える手を 握ろうとしたあの日は
On that day when I tried to hold your trembling hand
見えないモノを見ようとして 望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
Trying to see the invisible, I looked through the telescope
静寂を切り裂いて いくつも声が生まれたよ
Ripping through the silence, many voices were born
明日が僕らを呼んだって 返事もろくにしなかった
Even if tomorrow called us, we wouldn't even answer
「イマ」というほうき星 君と二人追いかけていた
The comet called 'Now', we were chasing it together
気が付けばいつだって ひたすら何か探している
Before I knew it, I was always searching for something
幸せの定義とか 哀しみの置き場とか
The definition of happiness, or a place for sadness
生まれたら死ぬまで ずっと探してる
From birth until death, I'll be searching forever
さぁ 始めようか 天体観測 ほうき星を探して
Now, shall we start our stargazing, searching for a comet?
今まで見つけたモノは 全部覚えている
Everything I've found so far, I remember it all
君の震える手を 握れなかった痛みも
Even the pain of not being able to hold your trembling hand
知らないモノを知ろうとして 望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
Trying to know the unknown, I looked through the telescope
暗闇を照らす様な 微かな光探したよ
I searched for a faint light, as if to illuminate the darkness
そうして知った痛みを 未だに僕は覚えている
And the pain I learned then, I still remember it even now
「イマ」というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
The comet called 'Now', I'm still chasing it alone
背が伸びるにつれて 伝えたい事も増えてった
As I grew taller, the things I wanted to tell you increased
宛名の無い手紙も 崩れる程重なった
Letters with no recipient, they piled up until they collapsed
僕は元気でいるよ 心配事も少ないよ
I'm doing well, I don't have many worries
ただひとつ 今も思い出すよ
But there's just one thing I still remember now
予報外れの雨に 打たれて泣きだしそうな
Being hit by unpredicted rain, as if about to cry
君の震える手を 握れなかったあの日の
On that day when I couldn't hold your trembling hand
見えてるモノを見落として 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Overlooking what was visible, I carried my telescope once again
静寂と暗闇の 帰り道を駆け抜けた
And ran through the way back, in the silence and darkness
そうして知った痛みが
The pain I came to know...
未だに僕を支えている
...still supports me even now.
「イマ」というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
The shooting star called "Now", I'm still chasing it alone.
もう一度君に会おうとして
Trying to meet you once more,
望遠鏡をまた担いで
I shoulder my telescope again.
前と同じ午前二時
2 AM, just like before,
フミキリまで駆けてくよ
I'll run to the railroad crossing.
始めようか天体観測
Shall we begin the stargazing?
二分後に君が来なくとも
Even if you don't come in two minutes.
「イマ」というほうき星
The shooting star called "Now",
君と二人追いかけている
I'm chasing it together with you.
なんでこんな疲れてんだ...
Why am I so tired...
めっちゃ踊ってくれたー！
You danced so much for us!
踊ってたっていうかパフォーマンス！
It wasn't just dancing, it was a performance!
二人でね、ほうき星探しに行ってたんだよね。
The two of us went looking for the shooting star, didn't we?
めっちゃ歩き回っちゃった！
I walked around so much!
全員ちょっとヘトヘト...
Everyone is a bit exhausted...
はじめはもう一曲目からもうヘトヘトですけれども。
Hajime has been exhausted since the first song, though.
でもね、このままちょっとらでんと番長の二人を聴きたいなーなんて思ってるんですけれども！
But you know, I was thinking I'd like to hear a bit of Raden and Bancho right now!
いいよ！いいよ！
Sure! Sure!
徒歩じゃなくて、チャリで駆け上がりますか！
Instead of walking, shall we dash up on a bike!
準備いいですか？
Are you ready?
はい！じゃあ音楽お願いします！
Yes! Then, music please!
夏色 / 北川悠仁 作詞・作曲
Natsuiro / Lyrics & Composition by Yujin Kitagawa
夏といえばでしょー！
It's summer, after all!
駐車場のネコは アクビをしながら
The cat in the parking lot is yawning,
今日も一日を過ごしてゆく
and spending another day.
何ら変わらない 穏やかな街並み
The peaceful cityscape hasn't changed at all.
みんな夏が来たって 浮かれ気分なのに 君は一人さえな顔してるネ
Even though everyone is in a festive mood because summer is here, you have a gloomy look on your face all by yourself.
そうだ君に
That's right, to you,
見せたい物があるんだ
there's something I want to show.
大きな五時半の夕焼け 子供の頃と同じように
The big sunset at 5:30, just like when we were kids.
海も空も雲も 僕等でさえも 染めていくから...
Because it's going to dye the sea, the sky, the clouds, and even us...
この長い長い下り坂を
Down this long, long downhill slope,
君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
with you riding on the back of my bicycle.
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
I'll grip the brakes tight,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
and we'll slowly, slowly go down.
風鈴の音でウトウトしながら 夢見心地で
Dozing off to the sound of wind chimes, in a dreamlike state,
ヨダレをたらしてる
and drooling.
Woh... いつもと同じ 網戸ごしの風の匂い
Woh... the same as always, the scent of the wind through the screen door.
休日でみんなも ゴロゴロしてるのに
Even though everyone is just lounging around on their day off,
君はずいぶん忙しい顔をしてるネ
you have such a busy-looking face.
そうだいつかの あの場所へ行こう
That's right, let's go to that place from that one time.
真夏の夜の波の音は 不思議な程心静かになる
The sound of the waves on a midsummer night makes one feel strangely calm.
少しだけ全て忘れて
Forget everything for just a little while,
波の音の中包み込まれていく
and be enveloped in the sound of the waves.
この細い細い裏道を抜けて
Going through this narrow, narrow back alley,
誰もいない大きな夜の海見ながら
while looking at the big, empty night sea,
線香花火に二人で
together, to our sparklers,
ゆっくりゆっくり火をつける
we'll slowly, slowly light them.
いつか君の涙が こぼれおちそうになったら
If your tears ever seem about to overflow,
何もしてあげられないけど 少しでもそばにいるよ...
I might not be able to do anything, but I'll be by your side, even if just a little...
この長い長い下り坂を
Down this long, long downhill slope,
君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
with you riding on the back of my bicycle.
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
I'll grip the brakes tight,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
and we'll slowly, slowly go down.
Slowly, slowly going down.
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
はーい！
Haa-i!
じゃあちょっと連続なんですけど、
Well, we're going back-to-back, but
あ、よいしょ。あ、足。
there we go. Ah, my leg.
最後4人で歌いたいと思います！
lastly, the four of us will sing together!
おー！
Oh!
よっしゃー！
Alright!
何を歌うんですか？
What are we singing?
何を歌うんだろうね？
I wonder what it could be?
じゃあ皆さん聞いてください。
Well then, everyone, please listen.
お願いします！
Here we go!
ウィーアー！
We are!
富、名声、力。
Wealth, fame, power.
この世のすべてを手に入れた男、海賊王ゴールド・ロジャー。
The man who obtained everything in this world, the Pirate King, Gold Roger.
彼の死にぎわに放った一言は人々を海へ駆り立てた。
His final words before his death drove people to the seas.
「俺の財宝か？ 欲しけりゃくれてやる。」
“My treasure? If you want it, it’s yours.”
「探せ！ この世のすべてをそこに置いてきた！」
“Find it! I left everything this world has to offer there!”
男たちはグランドラインを目指し夢を追い続ける。
Men head for the Grand Line to pursue their dreams.
世はまさに大海賊時代！
The world is truly in the Great Pirate Era!
ありったけの夢をかき集め
Gather up all your dreams
捜し物を捜しに行くのさ One Piece
And go in search of what you’re looking for! One Piece!
捜し物を捜しに行くのさ
And go in search of what you’re looking for
One Piece!
羅針盤なんて 渋滞のもと
A compass is just a cause for traffic
熱にうかされ 舵をとるのさ
Carried away by fever, I'll take the helm
ホコリかぶってた 宝の地図も
Even a dusty treasure map
確かめたのなら 伝説じゃない！
Is no longer a legend once you've confirmed it!
個人的な嵐は 誰かの
A personal storm is someone else's
バイオリズム 乗っかって
Biorhythm, just hop on it
思い過ごせばいい！
And let it pass through your mind!
ありったけの夢をかき集め
Gather up all your dreams
捜し物を捜しに行くのさ
And go in search of what you’re looking for
ポケットのコイン、それと
A coin in your pocket, and
You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ぜんぶまに受けて 信じちゃっても
Even if you take it all seriously and believe it
肩を押されて １歩リードさ
Getting a push on the shoulder gives you a one-step lead
今度会えたなら 話すつもりさ
If we can meet again, I plan to talk to you
それからのことと これからのこと
About what's happened since then and what's to come
つまりいつも ピンチは誰かに
In other words, a pinch is always
アピール出来る いいチャンス
A good chance to show off to someone
自意識過剰に！
With excessive self-consciousness!
しみったれた夜を ぶっとばせ！
Blow away the stingy night!
宝箱にキョウミは ないけれど
Though I have no interest in treasure chests
ポケットにロマン、それと
Romance in your pocket, and
You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ありったけの夢をかき集め
Gather up all your dreams
捜し物を捜しに行くのさ
And go in search of what you’re looking for
ポケットのコイン、それと
A coin in your pocket, and
You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ウィーアー！
We are!
イエーイ！ウィーアー！
Yay! We are!
やばいもう時間だ、時間だ！
Oh no, it's already time, it's time!
最後にお知らせがあります！
Lastly, we have some announcements!
あ、いう間だ...
Ah, in no time...
改めてになりますが、明日0時、つまり今日の24時に
Once again, tomorrow at 0:00, which is 24:00 today...
Midsummer Citrusがデジタルリリースされます！
Midsummer Citrus will be released digitally!
イエーイ！
Yay!
こちらあと4時間後くらいかな？聞けるようになります！
That's in about 4 hours? You'll be able to listen to it!
そして、来月の配信なんですが、いつも10日に
And about next month's stream, we usually do this
ReGLOSSのこの配信やってるんですけど
ReGLOSS stream on the 10th...
8月は8月1日に配信予定となっておりますので、
In August, the stream is scheduled for August 1st,
間違えないように注意してください。
so please be careful not to mistake the date.
1日だ！
The 1st!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
いや楽しかったねカラオケ。
Man, karaoke was fun.
あっという間だった...
It went by in a flash...
もぐもぐだけどね。
Even though I'm munching away.
全力でした！
I gave it my all!
美味しいもの食べるぞー！
I'm gonna eat something delicious!
そうだねー。
Yeah, let's.
見てくれた皆も楽しんでくれたかな？
I hope everyone watching had fun too?
よかったー！
I hope so!
たくさんのね、あの、アンケート回答もありがとうございました！
And thank you so much for all the survey responses!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
はい、じゃあ今日はこんなところで終わりましょうか。
Alright, then let's wrap it up here for today.
はーい！
Okay!
それではまた来月、お会いしましょう！
Well then, we'll see you again next month!
見てくれてありがとうね！バイバーイ！
Thanks for watching! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
新曲披露もあるよ！ 真夏のReGLOSSカラオケ
There's also a new song reveal! Midsummer ReGLOSS Karaoke